PRASHANT PANIGRAHI

Address: Krishna nagar, Jaggu Patel Chawl no. 3, Room no.3 90 feet road, Sakinaka. Mumbai- 400072. Contact: 9769322918

Email:prashantpanigrahi93@gmail.com



PROFILE

Aiming to achieve a challenging & successful career where I can make a significant contribution using my innovative ideas, knowledge, skills and experience with the objective of development & growth of the Organization. I have <u>3.3 years</u> of Professional experience in Angular 4+, MVC, C#, .Net and SQL Server.

Worked for "**Digitek Software**" as Software Developer from <u>Jan 2017 to Present.</u>
Worked for "**Merilent Inc**." as Associate Software Developer from August 2015 to Dec 2016.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- Completed B.E. in 2015 from Vidyalankar Institute of Technology in Information Technology course, affiliated to the University of Mumbai with an aggregate of 63.93%.
- Completed HSC in 2011(Maharashtra Board) from Ramniranjan Jhunjhunwala College with 83.00%.
- Completed SSC in 2009 (Maharashtra Board) from Yogiraj Shree Krishna Vidyalaya with 88.46%.

KEY SKILLS

- Technical: Angular 4+, C#, LINQ, Web API, .NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Entity framework.
- CMS: WordPress.
- Databases: SQL Server, MYSQL
- BI Tools: SSIS, SSRS.
- Tools & IDE: GitHub, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Notepad++, Blender (Animation), Word, PowerPoint, Excel, WebEx.
- Operating Systems: Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 10.

PROFESSIONAL STRENGTH

- Good knowledge and exposure in OOPS concept, .NET, Factory pattern, Singleton Pattern and Angular.
- Commitment to co-operative teamwork and involved in delivering high quality product to client.
- Schedule meetings and communicate with U.S. clients on phone for project details on WebEx. Also drafts mail and document for our client and in-house projects.
- A high tolerance of stress and enjoys responsibilities. Quick learner with good grasping ability.
- Discussing Innovative thoughts. Maintaining relations with affection.
- Eagerness to learn new things always.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Digitek Software

Software Developer

Jan 2017 to Present

1. Home Inspection 3.0: Patient Invoice: The main objective of this project is to take input from client form, generate reports, and view for home inspector, agent and quality inspector for insurance company.

Role: .Net Developer and UI developer

Technology: SQL, Entity framework, Web API (.NET 4.5), C# and Angular 5

Responsibilities: Worked on Frontend and Views, Stored Procedures and SQL queries.

Team Size: 3

Duration: 25th May 2018 to till date.

2. Patient Invoice: The main objective of this project is to generate invoice of treatment and gather patient details.

Role: .Net Developer and UI developer

Technology: SQL, Entity framework, Web API (.NET 4.5), C# and Angular 5

Responsibilities: Worked on Frontend and Views, Stored Procedures and SQL queries.

Team Size: 1

Duration: 15 days. (3rd May 2018 to 19th May 2018)

3. OMS: The main objective of this project is to take Order and Payment in offline mode and sync online on available of internet to SAP database. This is a hybrid application built using Cordova.

Role: .Net and UI Developer

Technology: SQL, Entity framework, Web API (.NET 4.5), C#, JavaScript, JQuery and Cordova

Responsibilities: Worked on Frontend and worked on Views, Stored Procedures and SQL queries.

Team Size: 1

Duration: 1 Month. (4th April 2018 to 4th May 2018)

4. ERP: The main objective of this project is to integrate sell and buy module with daily analysis report and inventory management

Role: .Net Developer and SSRS developer.

Technology: SQL, Entity framework, SSRS 2012, Web API (.NET 4.5), C#, XAF DevExpress.

Responsibilities: Worked on Frontend and worked on Views, Stored Procedures and SQL queries.

Team Size: 3

Duration: 6 Month. (26nd November 2017 to 3rd May 2018)

5. Home Inspection: The main objective of this project is to take input from client form and generate reports and view for home inspector, agent and quality inspector for insurance company.

Role: .Net Developer and SSRS developer.

Technology: SQL Server 2014, Entity framework, SSRS 2012, Web API (.NET 4.5) and C#.

Responsibilities: Worked on UI pages and worked on Views, Stored Procedures and SQL queries.

Developed Rest Services(API) using ASP.NET Web API and C#

Team Size: 4

Duration: 6 Month. (Completed started on 15nd May 2017 to 20th November 2017)

6. WordPress: Created E-Commerce and School site using WordPress and PHP.

Role: Developer and Tester

Technology: WordPress, PHP and MYSQL.

Team Size: 1

Duration: 14 days (Completed started on 25nd April 2017 to 10th May 2017)

7. Angular Form Builder

Create a Framework for front end user to build form. This will create backend automatically for CRUD operations.

Role: Developer and Tester

Technology: AngularJs, C#, .Net, SQL

Team Size: 1

Duration: 2 Months. (Completed started on 2nd Feb 2017 to 10th April 2017)

Merilent Inc.

Associate Software Developer

August 2015 – Dec 2016

1. Dock Manager Framework: This is a framework gives ability of multi-window layout manager for Web Apps (built on top of Golden Layout) and also user can save layout.

Role: Junior Developer.

Technology: Entity framework, AngularJS, Golden Layout, Web API (.NET 4.5) and C#, SQL.

Responsibilities:

- · Worked on Views, Stored Procedures and SQL queries and for saving user layout
- Developed Rest Services(API) using ASP.NET Web API and C#

Team Size: 2

Duration: 5 Month (completed started on 5th June 2017 to 25th November 2017)

2. Authorization Framework: This is a Framework to secure Intranet Application and gives the ability to user for Single Sign on and Single Sign out (built on top of ADFS).

Role: Developer

Technology: ADFS (Active Directory Federation Services), AD (Active Directory), Web API (.NET 4.5) and C#, SQL Server, Entity framework

Responsibilities:

- Worked on Views, Stored Procedures and SQL queries for storing user roles.
- Developed Rest Services(API) using ASP.NET Web API and C#

Team Size: 1

Duration: 5 Month (completed started on 1st Jan 2016 to 25th May 2016)

3. Project: Feed Processor Description:

The main objective of this project is to generate reports and recon data from daily trade. We get xml files from client to process into staging table and finally to Data Warehouse, using this data reports are generated for client in different formats (.csv, .pdf)

Role: Junior Developer.

Technology: SQL Server 2014, SSIS 2012, Entity framework, SSRS 2012, Web API (.NET 4.5) and C#.

Responsibilities:

- Extracted Data from sources like xml Files.
- Extensively worked on Views, Stored Procedures and SQL queries and for loading the data (staging) to enhance and maintain the existing functionality.
- Developed Rest Services(API) using ASP.NET Web API and C#

Team Size: 2

Duration: 5 Month (completed started on 20th August 2015 to 25th December 2015)

EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Coordinator in the Carom event held in college fest (VERVE) in 2013.
- Got selected as Microsoft Student Partner for the year 2012-2014.
- Part of technological event held by Microsoft (Bootcampus 2013).
- Participated in field of art at Apsara Excellence held on 29th January, 2006.
- Participated in Painting contest organized by CIART held on 27th February, 2006.
- Participated in Painting contest organized by Bhartiya Manav Samaj Vikas Kendra held on 27th February, 2006.

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENT

- Our Final Year (B.E.) project won 1st prize in college from IT Department.
- Passed the Elementary grade drawing examination held in the year 2006 in grade C
- Passed the Intermediate grade drawing examination held in the year 2007 in grade C
- Awarded as third best student in field of education from Yogiraj Shree Krishna Vidyalaya in the year 2008-2009.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- Date of birth: 27th August 1993.
- Gender: Male.
- Marital Status: Single.
- Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi and Oriya.
- Interests: Playing console games, Chess, Listening Music.
- LinkedIn: https://in.linkedin.com/in/prashant-panigrahi-2488a258
- **GitHub**: https://github.com/Merilent/Authorization